>> Brian Holt: 让我们在整个周期中工作。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Let's work
through this whole cycle.
我知道我在这里已经采取了很多步骤。
I recognize that I have
introduced a lot of steps here.
所以让我们在整个过程中
So let's work through the entire
cycle of beginning to end
发生了什么好吗
of what happens here, okay?
首先我在这儿有搜索的地方对吧
First thing,
I have search params here, right?
所以这是第一次呈现。
So this gets rendered for the first time.
得到这些信息把这些钩子都设置好
It gets all this information,
sets all these hooks up so
第一位是西雅图华盛顿
the first location is Seattle, Washington.
Breed 将会是一个空的数组动物将会成为一只狗
Breed is gonna be an empty array and
animal is going to be a dog, and
会有一个空的串对吧
breed is going to be an empty string,
right?
>> Brian Holt: 然后将调度此 useEffect，但是
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: It's then going
to schedule this useEffect, but
这事还没发生对吧
this is not actually gonna happen yet,
right?
此操作不会在第一个呈示时运行，行吗 ?
This does not run on the first render,
okay?
然后它将返回所有这些标记，
Then it's going to return
all of this markup,
>> Brian Holt: 对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Right?
然后它就会把所有这些都呈现给 DOM
Then its going to finish that, it's
going to render that all to the DOM so
用户会先看到这一切的好吗
the user's going to see all of this first,
okay?
之后，它将会运行调度效果。
Then after that,
it's going to run the schedule effect.
记住你能在这里产生 10 个效应对吧
Keep in mind you can have
ten effects in here, right?
现在我们只有一个效应，但是你可以在这里产生很多影响。
Right now we just have one effect,
but you can have many effects in here.
所以在第一次渲染之后，它就会在这里调用这个函数。
So after the first render, it's going
to call this function right here.
>> Brian Holt: 因此，这将分隔为空数组。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So this is going
to separates to be empty array.
它会导致单独的字符串。
It's gonna cause separate
to be an empty string.
> > Brian Holt: 然后，
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: And then,
它会向 API， >> Brian Holt: 用动物，
it's gonna go out to the API,
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: With animal,
它会从 API 中恢复，然后会调用 setBreeds。
and it's going to get breeds back from the
API, and then it's gonna call setBreeds.
但是记住这需要一些时间，对吧 ?
But keep in mind,
this is gonna take some time, right?
这将会是第二次或者类似的事情，对吧 ?
This will take a second or
something like that, right?
接下来会发生什么呢 ?
So what's gonna happen is
it's going to render, and
然后再等这个从 API的品种串回来
then a second later once this comes back
with the breed strings from the API,
这会导致另一人重新呈现对吧
it's gonna cause another re-render, right?
但是这里唯一改变的是品种
But, the only thing that's
changed here is breeds.
这一特殊影响是否取决于品种?
Does this particular
effect depend on breeds?
没有，对吧 ?
No, right?
所以下次不会再重述了吧
So it doesn't re-render the next time,
right?
因为品种变了但动物， setBreed 和 setBreeds
Because breeds changed, but
animal, setBreed, and setBreeds,
都没有变化对吧
none of these changed, right?
所以它只运行一次，然后就完成了，好吗 ?
So it just runs that effect once and
then it's done, okay?
所以现在，我要在地点第二次去，对吧 ?
So now, fathom for a second that go and
I type in the location, right?
现在，位置已更新。
So now location is updated state.
它会在这里使用，它说嘿，有动物的 setBreed 或者
And it goes here to useEffect and
it says hey, has animal setBreed or
自从上次我运行这种效应以来， setBreeds 变了吗 ?
setBreeds changed since last
time I ran this effect?
没有，对吧 ?
No, right?
因此，它不会将此影响安排为再次运行，到目前为止还不错吗 ?
So it does not schedule this
effect to run again, good so far?
好，然后我进去，我选择动物，它是狗，现在它是猫。
Okay, then I go in and I select animal
to be, it was dog and now it's cat.
所以它会重新呈现但它说
So it's gonna re-render but it says,
哎，动物变了，是吧 ?
hey, did animal change, it did, right?
我把它从狗变成了猫
I changed it from dog to cat.
所以它会立即将它设置为空数组，并且
So it's gonna set immediately set
breeds to be empty array, and
空字符串将调用该 API，请重新获取新种
empty string is going to then call
the API, get the new breeds back and
在那之后它就会重新呈现
it's gonna re-render again after that.
>> Brian Holt: 这有道理吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: That makes sense?
>> Brian Holt: 因此，这就是使用状态和
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So this is how useState and
useEffects 协同工作，以管理此类状态更新。
useEffects work together to kind of
manage these kind of state updates.
>> 扬声器 2: 对于确定是否为
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So for
the dependency array that determines if
useEffect 运行，该函数运行。
useEffect is run, that functions run.
当我们放进 setBreed 和 setBreeds时
When we put in setBreed and setBreeds,
我们只是说如果他们重新分配了就会重新运行
we're just saying basically if those were
reassigned and then it would rerun it.
>> Brian Holt: 你把这件事提起来很有趣。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: That's funny
that you bring this up.
我和几个 React 进行了一段时间的讨论
I had an at-length discussion
with a couple of the React
核心团队成员我觉得这很傻因为这永远不会改变
core team members of I think that's silly,
because that's never gonna change.
他们基本上说，我们不管，还是去做。
And they basically said,
we don't care, do it anyway.
我觉得这样更好，因为这更清楚你的意图，对吧 ?
I would think this is better because this
is more clear about your intention, right?
只在动物运行时运行。
Only at run when animal runs.
但你会得到一个错误， >> Brian Holt: SetBreed 需要
But you're gonna get an error of,
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: SetBreed needs to
在那里
be in there.
所以我放弃了这就是社区所做的
So I gave up,
this is what the community's doing,
所以我在教你社区的工作
so I'm teaching you what
the community's doing.
我是说理论上这不是个坏主意对吧
I mean, in theory,
it's not a bad idea, right?
我想理论上是可以更新的之类的
I guess in theory it could be updated or
something like that, but whatever,
我不知道我不知道
I don't know.
>> 扬声器 3: 所以它只是在寻找
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So it's just looking for
您在该功能中使用的任何外部变量吗 ?
any external variable that
you're using in that function?
> > Brian Holt: 对，这里的想法是我有 setBreed，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Right, so the idea here
being that I have setBreed, right?
如果我使用 setBreed 因为它是在这里定义的
And if I'm using setBreed because
it's defined in here inside of this
功能本身就意味着如果这个 setBreed 的任何时间都改变了
function itself, that means if any
time this setBreed does change,
它应该重新运行效果。
it should re-run the effect.
这就是动物对吧
Which is true of Animal, right?
我在这里用动物所以任何动物都改变了
I'm using Animal here, so
any time that Animal changes,
我需要重新发挥作用。
I need to re-run the effect.
这就是他们在追的东西，这会救你的，对吧 ?
So that's what they're chasing after,
this will save you bugs, right?
因为如果我没有动物在这里
Because if I didn't have Animal in here,
其实这件事对你很有利
actually this would be
a good thing to show you.
所以如果我带动物离开这里它会第一次请求
So if I take Animal out of here,
it will request it the first time, and
我要去找澳大利亚牧羊人对吧
I'm gonna get Australian shepherd, right?
但如果我把它改为猫它就不会更新了
But if I change this to be cat now,
it's not gonna update.
对，因为它不可能回到 API 上，因为它认为我是好的，
Right, because it's not gonna go back to
the API because it thinks like, I'm good,
对，我不需要改变，因为，我不依赖动物。
right, I don't have to change,
because, I don't depend on animal.